[{"id": "59decf1dea2747c8aff16d1a", "question": "In horse racing how many Furlongs are in a mile?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5a", "question": "What New York cardiologist published his bestselling \"Diet Revolution\" in 1972?", "answer": "Robert Atkins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e8", "question": "What island nation was invaded by US troops in October 1983?", "answer": "Grenada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6bb96fb6c85e9e634ff56", "question": "Managua is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Nicaragua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe73377eec85e375820b221", "question": "What was the name of the antisemitic laws passed in Nazi Germany on September 15, 1935?", "answer": "Nuremberg Law", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5952413d736d4be723796b61", "question": "Which superhero was created by Mike Young, as a way to help his child sleep at night?", "answer": "SuperTed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ecae3ef790ded87bb38fd8b", "question": "What word descirbes \"a serious disagreement or argument\"?", "answer": "Conflict", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b73e06d333868d34d6f8", "question": "Who was the British Navy Minister during World War I?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909ccb3bb53d1af658864e2", "question": "Which composer wrote the classical piece \"Messiah\"?", "answer": "George Frideric Handel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01b", "question": "Who was US's first Postmaster General?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f40", "question": "Drug lord Mr. Big is the villain of what James Bond movie?", "answer": "Live and Let Die", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad5", "question": "How many zeroes are in the number one trillion?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a4", "question": "Which famous duo released the hit song \"Ebony & Ivory\"?", "answer": "Paul McCartney and Stevie Wonder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa41fbc73aa70ea0b70b12", "question": "Which port city was the first capital of Pakistan?", "answer": "Karachi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea82e4ff048f679a45ac24", "question": "How many zeros are in a quadrillion?", "answer": "15", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010ca2e0775fa611bce67f4", "question": "Which famed beauty company was named in part for its founder's sister?", "answer": "Maybelline -- Thomas Lyle Williams developed a product for darkening eyebrows and eyelashes and named it after his sister Mabel.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cf", "question": "Who played the role of Julia Brougham in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Loretta Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339258", "question": "Who performed the song \"The Power of Love\" with his band in the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Huey Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c94", "question": "Who wrote the poem \"The Road Not Taken\"?", "answer": "Robert Frost", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69cdd20565ad31a57c770", "question": "What was the name of the Mayflower's sister ship?", "answer": "Speedwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fed2bbaec223966ae8f8911", "question": "What is the name of the smelly green ghost in \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Slimer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c927", "question": "How many feet are there in a nautical mile?", "answer": "6,076", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c5f", "question": "The movie \"American Graffiti\" was released in what year?", "answer": "1973", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eae20f83302ff91e46484", "question": "Which creature was the Egyptian God Horus identified with?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d5", "question": "In the standard Monopoly game, how much money do you collect for finishing second in a beauty contest?", "answer": "$10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49e", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339984", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Barney's snowplowing business?", "answer": "Plow King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f9", "question": "What is better than scissors in the paper, stone, scissors game?", "answer": "Stone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4f", "question": "What LSU Tiger was drafted by the Orlando Magic in 1992?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7f", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Abe Ravelstein in the novel \"Ravelstein\"?", "answer": "Allan Bloom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb3", "question": "Which cuisine gave us kimchi and bulgogi?", "answer": "Korean", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56c", "question": "Phobos is the name of one of the moons of which planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c76", "question": "What horror movie title character will appear if you chant his name five times in a mirror?", "answer": "Candyman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77a", "question": "What large reptile was popularized by Steve Irwin and Paul Hogan?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339916", "question": "What was the name of Vince Vaughn\u2019s gymnasium in \u201cDodgeball: A True Underdog Story\u201d?", "answer": "Average Joe's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017380944491cbd7c5a1793", "question": "During World War II, prisoners wearing an uninverted red triangle in a concentration camp signified the prisoners were what?", "answer": "An enemy\u00a0POW, a spy or traitor, a military\u00a0deserter\u00a0or a military criminal.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca4", "question": "What is the heating element in Hasbro's Easy-Bake Oven\"?", "answer": "A lightbulb", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7340ceec85e375820b22c", "question": "What German fighter pilot was credited with 80 air combat victories during World War I?", "answer": "Manfred von Richthofen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aecf", "question": "Shortly after the start of the Spanish-American War, the US Navy blockaded what island?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae99", "question": "Established in 1607, what settlement was founded by John Smith in Virginia?", "answer": "Jamestown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a025", "question": "What is the name of the female field reporter for Channel 5 News in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Tricia Takanawa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c3049076251badbeacf", "question": "Which unique pet did Calvin Coolidge have during his presidency?", "answer": "Raccoon -- Named Rachel, she might be the most well known pet.  She walked around on a leash and was the master of mischief.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4a3949076251badbeab1", "question": "In which Texas city will you find the famous Alamo?", "answer": "San Antonio -- The old mission was the site of a doomed battle in Texas\u2019s war for independence from Mexico.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc1", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by The Mamas and the Papas?", "answer": "Monday, Monday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede5c16ce05a3942286df0", "question": "What is the only product Elvis Presley ever did a live TV commercial for?", "answer": "Southern Maid Donuts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c363", "question": "What part of the body does an orthopedic doctor treat?", "answer": "Bones", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b6", "question": "In the \"Great Upheaval\", three quarters of what people were forcibly removed from Nova Scotia?", "answer": "The Acadians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c3", "question": "Pitchblende is the primary source for which fuel?", "answer": "Uranium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbd", "question": "What popular designer was responsible for the wardrobe of \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b29", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon character was always causing trouble for Ranger Smith?", "answer": "Yogi Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b16", "question": "What cartoon character was introduced as \"Mi Laoshu\" in China?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590722e33745b36be7303a03", "question": "What popular Christmas song did Eartha Kitt record in 1953?", "answer": "Santa Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a290", "question": "What name did Cat Stevens adopt in 1977?", "answer": "Yusuf Islam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a072", "question": "What planet did Alf come from?", "answer": "Melmac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d8", "question": "How many fluid ounces in a gill?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe1f165145fb29466707392", "question": "As used in English, what is the meaning of the Latin phrase \"caveat emptor\"?", "answer": "Let the buyer beware", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7ddbff048f679a45ac00", "question": "Anthropophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "People or society", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049988cf93664eb1048691", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e36", "question": "What game show host took his stage name from the college in his West Virginia hometown?", "answer": "Peter Marshall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974e", "question": "What are the names of the members of Pentatonix?", "answer": "Scott, Mitch, Avi, Kirsten, and Kevin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ef", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 505?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77d47124f0f7a362efd557", "question": "In the novel and movie \"Hitchhikers Guide to The Galaxy,\" what is the most important thing a hitchhiker can carry?", "answer": "A towel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b892", "question": "What is the highest score in darts from three different doubles?", "answer": "114", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1db", "question": "Which retail entrepreneur founded \"The Body Shop\" in 1976?", "answer": "Anita Roddick", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0f", "question": "In what country is Guinness Stout brewed?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c0", "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure of any animal?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339377", "question": "How many Oscars did the 1997 movie \"Titanic\" win?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbf806ce05a3942286f00", "question": "In the television series \"Magnum P.I.\", Magnum often wore a ball cap for which sport's team?", "answer": "Detroit Tigers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69dba20565ad31a57c77b", "question": "In what year did the U.S. Census begin?", "answer": "1790", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600243b84be4723ccac2219a", "question": "Which semi-autobiographical novel by James Baldwin tells the story of John Grimes, a Harlem teenager in the 1930s?", "answer": "\"Go Tell It on the Mountain\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b216", "question": "Who was assassinated by Yigal Amir?", "answer": "Yitzhak Rabin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b844", "question": "A Virgin Mary is a Bloody Mary without which ingredient?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a585", "question": "Which of the New England states is the largest in size?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ddb406d333868d34d707", "question": "Who was known as the \"Mad Monarch\"?", "answer": "George III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590679b5ff9c0647b50a8051", "question": "On January 1, 2016, which Canadian province became the first one to allow the testing of self-driving vehicles on public roads?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c8a6d690aac110e4167081", "question": "How many milliliters is a teaspoon?", "answer": "5 mL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65d991f3c0ead6880d61e", "question": "Who was Moses' sister in the Bible?", "answer": "Miriam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b9", "question": "What actor plays the role of Evan Treborn in the movie \"The Butterfly Effect\"?", "answer": "Ashton Kucher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7f", "question": "Ronald Reagan made headlines in 1980 for claiming that 80 percent of air pollution comes from what?", "answer": "Trees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa5289c73aa70ea0b70b1b", "question": "Which country serves as the home of the largest farm in the world?", "answer": "The Mudanjiang City Mega Farm is located in China and takes up almost 23 million acres.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76f3eeec85e375820b2e5", "question": "What is the most mountainous country in Europe?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a644", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Buckeye State\"?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c5", "question": "Venation is used to describe what item found in nature?", "answer": "Leaves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84b", "question": "The Ryder Cup is awarded in what sport?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339480", "question": "What is the name of Goldie Hawn's daughter who starred in the 2000 movie \"Almost Famous\"?", "answer": "Kate Hudson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac27", "question": "The Panama Canal connects the Gulf of Panama and which sea?", "answer": "Caribbean sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c0", "question": "What kind of store did John Travolta\u2019s character work at in the movie \"Saturday Night  Fever\"?", "answer": "Hardware store", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b0e98e964118b2bb3809cc", "question": "On what day in February was the 2010 romantic comedy film \"Valentine\u2019s Day\" released?", "answer": "February 10", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b88a", "question": "In which decade was the first aluminum bat used in professional baseball?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c997", "question": "What colour bill does a Greylag goose have?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fed2893ec223966ae8f890b", "question": "\"2001: A Space Odyssey\" features which artificially-intelligent computer?", "answer": "HAL 9000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdb6ee347d002c297e4dd", "question": "What does the energiser bunny wear on his feet?", "answer": "Flip flops", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3813815febcc896f9279", "question": "What is the eigth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Scorpio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60a", "question": "What is an alloy?", "answer": "A metal mixed with an element", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6012189c63c99d48cd169af6", "question": "Where were the fortune cookies invented?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a13", "question": "What is the name of the dog in the musical \"Annie\"?", "answer": "Sandy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a961", "question": "In terms of land area, what are the three largest countries bordering China to the north?", "answer": "Russia, Mongolia and Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3417ff048f679a45aaf5", "question": "What chemical makes plants green?", "answer": "Chlorophyll", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f1781e4b8195c09b948d5c2", "question": "Which abolitionist wrote the newspapers called \"The Liberator\"?", "answer": "William Lloyd Garrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbc906f60f0007efaba0e53", "question": "How many squares are there on the traditional \"Snakes & Ladders\" board?", "answer": "100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c9f72db4e2c7fbd3896746", "question": "Where did Thomas Lipton open his first grocery store?", "answer": "Glasgow, Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5fb05dad637d903c8827", "question": "The Vatican owns a telescope in what U.S. state?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3cf9e4f032c0db195b491", "question": "In which caste would you most likely find a Hindu priest?", "answer": "Traditionally, priests have come from the Brahmin varna.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339783", "question": "What album earned the Bee Gees a Grammy Award in 1978?", "answer": "Saturday Night Fever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76685eec85e375820b282", "question": "What is the Japanese word for \"dog\"?", "answer": "Inu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab0c04baab681b09292167", "question": "What 2005 horror short film shares a name with a piece of jewelry?", "answer": "Rings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b8", "question": "What boxer appeared in the broadway musical \"Buck White\" in 1969?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c52f", "question": "What is the nearest star to Earth?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad41", "question": "What was the name of the plane that dropped the atomic bomb on Hiroshima?", "answer": "Enola Gay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b014", "question": "The Orient Express is a train route between what two cities?", "answer": "Paris and Istanbul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b307", "question": "On what island is King Arthur buried?", "answer": "Avalon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e8", "question": "What country borders Libya on the East?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a137", "question": "Which character from \"Beavis and Butthead\" has their own show?", "answer": "Daria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339635", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Jasmine?", "answer": "Aladdin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58d", "question": "By what name is the spinal disease \"amyotrophic lateral sclerosis\" better known?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig's disease", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6e", "question": "Who developed the processed cheese spread known as Cheez Whiz?", "answer": "Edwin Traisman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c6e0fbde8045e48466bb", "question": "How is Lyme disease transmitted?", "answer": "The bite of blacklegged ticks infected with the bacterium\u00a0Borrelia burgdorferi\u00a0or rarely,\u00a0the bacterium Borrelia mayonii.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe937d86bd93ce3a4e5f679", "question": "Gynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Women", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f9f492aaf848b908361b87a", "question": "Which legume can be processed to make dynamite?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b62ce662d71a53651003", "question": "\"Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica\" was written by whom?", "answer": "Isaac Newton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe90a2201dd7bf43be5e896", "question": "The psychological test of human emotions and personality, using inkblots, is formally known as what?", "answer": "The Rorschach test", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4db", "question": "What do you get when you mix tequila, triple sec and lime juice?", "answer": "A Margarita", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8b0bec223966ae8f8836", "question": "Michael Jackson's \"Thriller\" was produced by which iconic music producer?", "answer": "Quincy Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b6", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives was the mother of Queen Elizabeth I?", "answer": "Anne Boleyn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b15", "question": "What is the name of the bar Peter Griffin and his buddies frequent on \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "The Drunken Clam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c697", "question": "In the human body, what is produced by the Islets of Langerhans?", "answer": "Insulin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f4affa5fdd6dd25324e3", "question": "Bangui is the capital of which land-locked African country?", "answer": "Central African Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8bd", "question": "What is the more common name for Umbilicus?", "answer": "Belly button", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c607", "question": "The Asteroid Belt can be found between which two planets?", "answer": "Mars and Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbf206ce05a3942286efb", "question": "Who was the male lead in the film \"American Gigolo\"?", "answer": "Richard Gere", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a3c837f039f3d7859290ff9", "question": "In the TV Show \"Gunsmoke\", what was Festus\u2019 occupation prior to becoming Marshall Dillon\u2019s deputy?", "answer": "Wolfer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec242e8dc25ca9e12ef636", "question": "What color is the car that Starsky drives in the TV show \"Starsky & Hutch\"?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be86", "question": "What type of a tree killed Sonny Bono?", "answer": "Pine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fb", "question": "In the 1998 movie \"You've Got Mail\", Joe and Kelly are in what business?", "answer": "Book retailing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cf85877e98cb97778a4f", "question": "What is the state bird of Mississippi?", "answer": "Northern Mockingbird", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31d", "question": "How many camels carried the 117,000 volumes of Abdul Kassem Ismael's library?", "answer": "400", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a53", "question": "What is the subtitle of the classic novel \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\"?", "answer": "Life Among the Lowly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c455877e98cb9777899d", "question": "Where is the oldest brewery in North America?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a365", "question": "What country did the Venetian blinds originate in?", "answer": "Persia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2cfdc2596a59cbdfbd374", "question": "Who said, \u201cWorthless people love only to eat and drink; people of worth eat and drink only to live\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ce", "question": "In a P2P network, what does the \"P\" stand for?", "answer": "Peer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58be2d7d8faf425cf37add7f", "question": "The game \"Cities: Skylines\" was developed by which Finnish video game company?", "answer": "Colossal Order", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a7f5ae6f5f79087132fb40", "question": "Grace Murray Hopper, Jean Sammet, and Saul Gorn were the main developers of which business-oriented computer language?", "answer": "COBOL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b5", "question": "A quincentenary celebrates how many years?", "answer": "500", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ba", "question": "A gift of china is given to celebrate the anniversary of how many years of marriage?", "answer": "20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d46c2596a59cbdfbd3a3", "question": "Which bone exists as five separate bones when you are an infant?", "answer": "Cranium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ec7227f57c9fcac0ce71976", "question": "What is the longest running sporting event in the United States?", "answer": "The Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a27712f2a7826b9b871c", "question": "Which footballer starred in the film \"Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels\"?", "answer": "Vinnie Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c542", "question": "What plant does the Colorado beetle attack?", "answer": "Potato", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594a63a32ebb971c1417fb9b", "question": "Who played the Girl on the Motorcycle in the 1968 film of same name?", "answer": "Marianne Faithful", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ffa863a3a814d89068c5c", "question": "Winkle is a species of edible what?", "answer": "Sea snails", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f7", "question": "On what continent is the Balkan Peninsula?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd8", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"I\"?", "answer": "India", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03f", "question": "What is Peter's TV network called on the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "PTV", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc9f", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Fistmele\"?", "answer": "Archery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa74f73838c5c8a417f37", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f71c1a9e54d890926f6e5", "question": "Texas is home to the longest-running what?", "answer": "State fair -- Lasting 24 days, the Texas State Fair is one of Dallas's most popular events.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ca", "question": "A tree which is deciduous does what?", "answer": "Loses its leaves every year", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5904a40fcf93664eb10486c1", "question": "Despite being referred to as Francine throughout the \"Strangers in Paradise\" comic book series, what is this character\u2019s real first name?", "answer": "Helen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f2", "question": "Who played the part of \"Bluebottle\" in a popular radio comedy series?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339170", "question": "What popular Australian pop star sang the words \"All Beauty Must Die\"?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab0", "question": "Limnology is the study of what?", "answer": "Inland waters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59bb2a0ec9bff04efae6d75b", "question": "Who had a No. 1 hit in 1965 with the song \"I'm Alive\"?", "answer": "The Hollies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8591ec223966ae8f8807", "question": "Who directed both \"Frankenstein\" and \"The Invisible Man\"?", "answer": "James Whale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f766b4e2c7fbd3896748", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3f88ff048f679a45ab60", "question": "What type of birthmark is also called a stork bite?", "answer": "Salmon Patches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e87", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Faun?", "answer": "Human and goat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b77b", "question": "What 1990's fad involved something known as a slammer?", "answer": "Pogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91a", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Bragg?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f265cee580c7f8fd1e52", "question": "Who said, \"Winners never quit, and quitters never win.\"?", "answer": "Vince Lombardi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92d", "question": "What game has the winner striking the loser's wrist with two extended fingers?", "answer": "Rock, Paper, Scissors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9d", "question": "Na is the chemical symbol for which element?", "answer": "Sodium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3c", "question": "For whom is the left-field foul pole at Boston's Fenway Park officially named?", "answer": "Carlton Fisk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b7", "question": "What are brails and buntlines on a ship?", "answer": "Ropes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338baf", "question": "The Answer to the Great Question of Life, the universe and everything is what?", "answer": "42", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399eb", "question": "How many of the seven dwarfs had mustaches?", "answer": "None", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81bfed0de9af39e9d467e", "question": "The term \"ok\" caught on during what president's campaign?", "answer": "Martin Van Buren", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5cd", "question": "Buzzards Bay separates mainland Massachusetts from what land mass?", "answer": "Cape Cod", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf7", "question": "How many hits does it take to sink the submarine in the game of \"Battleship\"?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd661f6a5bfecdd737e0840", "question": "What country has hosted the most Olympics?", "answer": "USA", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7388feec85e375820b263", "question": "Which country is known as the Land of White Elephant?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59524570736d4be723796b6d", "question": "What are the dots on dominoes called?", "answer": "Pips, nips or dobs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1cb", "question": "Which group had a hit with the song \"Back for Good\" in 1995?", "answer": "Take That", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9c", "question": "New Mexico, California and which other state did the US gain after the Mexican War?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be2f", "question": "How many players are there in a standard baseball team?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133890e", "question": "Who founded the cubism movement with George Braque?", "answer": "Pablo Picasso", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c493", "question": "What animal has been dubbed nature's skyscraper?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51cf7ff04d658268c9320", "question": "What fraction of a person did slaves originally count as in the U.S. Constitution?", "answer": "3/5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7a", "question": "What country's space travellers have been called \"taikonauts\" since 1998?", "answer": "China's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6000ed369a72b906b34e3cea", "question": "Which scientist formulated the law of universal gravitation?", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e8", "question": "What year did the Gran Turismo game series first debut?", "answer": "1997", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a006", "question": "What movie kills off a racehorse named Khartoum?", "answer": "The Godfather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c668", "question": "What falcon is the fastest bird in North America?", "answer": "Peregrine Falcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd3", "question": "Hamilton is the capital of which British Overseas Territory?", "answer": "Bermuda", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e5dffe83fe1f2a824bc6", "question": "Who was \"The Lady Bandit of Arizona\"?", "answer": "Pearl Hart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1d", "question": "What M-word means the words at the bottom of a coat of arms?", "answer": "Motto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb67065ff7d326b622a96", "question": "Who had 1960's hits with \"Glad All Over\" and \"Bits and Pieces\"?", "answer": "The Dave Clark Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394aa", "question": "Who claims to have invented the name \"Remington Steele\"?", "answer": "Laura Holt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c30", "question": "What is the setting for most of John Steinbeck's novels?", "answer": "Rural farms", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9d", "question": "What is the profession of Jon Cryer's character on the TV show \"Two and a Half Men\"?", "answer": "Chiropractor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb95", "question": "Since 1909, what women's magazine has guaranteed its advertiser\u2019s products with a \"seal of approval\"?", "answer": "Good Housekeeping", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b5717fb67df192a942e335a", "question": "Which famous mystery writer created a mystery by disappearing in 1926?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c006", "question": "What name is given to a year with 366 days?", "answer": "Leap", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec22f68dc25ca9e12ef62b", "question": "As whom was J\u00e1n Ludv\u00edk Hyman Binyamin Hoch better known?", "answer": "Robert Maxwell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dbe2e748bb36357acdd9", "question": "What is the smallest marine mammal?", "answer": "The Sea otter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b17", "question": "What was the first name of Julia Roberts' character in the 2001 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "Tess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ef", "question": "What language does the word \"algebra\" come from?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef92e66ce05a3942286e88", "question": "Who is the first mainstream artist known for utilizing the infamous Auto-Tune vocal distortion technique?", "answer": "Cher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc06", "question": "A crusiverbalist is someone who is skilled at what?", "answer": "The creation or solving of crosswords", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afad", "question": "Off of which European coastline was the \"Battle of Trafalgar\" fought?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a5", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named for the father of Pelops?", "answer": "Tantalum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925d", "question": "What 1981 movie required some 7,000 snakes?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728c336bcd28c119383282", "question": "What is the name of Christopher Lee's autobiography?", "answer": "Tall, Dark and Gruesome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea36adff048f679a45ab11", "question": "What gentle sea mammals are also known as \"sea cows\"?", "answer": "Manatees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59220535a4edfd43a087ade8", "question": "How high is the center of the tennis court net?", "answer": "3 feet, or 91 centimetres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f1", "question": "What wondrous creation was designed by Sostratus of Cnidus?", "answer": "Lighthouse of Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7fa", "question": "In what gland is human growth hormone produced?", "answer": "The pituitary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e3", "question": "What is the most common ending for a city, town, village or hamlet in England?", "answer": "-ton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b745", "question": "What Biblical name literally means \"the sunny one\"?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a786", "question": "In which US state is Puget Sound located?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64b", "question": "In cakes, what is the difference between icing and frosting?", "answer": "There is no difference", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa01", "question": "What country celebrates its National Day on 17th May?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd4", "question": "Which state is the Hoover Dam located in?", "answer": "It lies on the border between Arizona and Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c223", "question": "Petroselinum crispum is the Latin name of which herb?", "answer": "Parsley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c370", "question": "What layer of the Earth's atmosphere sits between the troposphere and mesosphere?", "answer": "Stratosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600781c2bd51d85e222ab64f", "question": "How many versions of The Scream did Edvard Munch create?", "answer": "There are\u00a0five separate versions of the work - four paintings and a lithograph stone from which as many as 45 prints were made.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bebf", "question": "Sepp Blatter and Jack Warner are former executives from which international sports organization?", "answer": "FIFA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade2", "question": "Who founded the Han Dynasty?", "answer": "Liu Bang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f4ae5cb9e8bda6821369", "question": "Approximatly when did construction of the Colosseum finish?", "answer": "80 AD", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe738d1eec85e375820b268", "question": "In which country do people traditionally eat at KFC for Christmas?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e1fefe83fe1f2a824b9b", "question": "What was Hitler\u2019s primary justification for invading Russia?", "answer": "Germany needed more space for its population.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7be71877e98cb97778960", "question": "What is the coldest sea on Earth?", "answer": "White Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3e09ff048f679a45ab58", "question": "In 1906, a call for higher vitamin intakes was made to decrease outbreaks of which ailments?", "answer": "Scurvy and Ricketts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a525", "question": "The Hollywood Walk of Fame is located along what street?", "answer": "Hollywood Boulevard", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f24", "question": "What actor did Michael J. Fox replace as Marty McFly in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Eric Stolz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b29", "question": "What artistic technique requires painting watercolors directly onto wet plaster?", "answer": "Fresco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5eb", "question": "In which country is Angel Falls located?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbee06ce05a3942286ef8", "question": "Who recorded the song \"King for a Day\"?", "answer": "Thompson Twins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c2", "question": "What is Albumen the correct term for?", "answer": "Egg White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff25a6431a458464a93c471", "question": "What group of animals is called a \"flink\"?", "answer": "A group of 12 or more cows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989ac89cb8751d53e7d760a", "question": "When was the polka dot jersey first awarded at the Tour de France to the \"King of the Mountains\"?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d0770c870e6f05ba600861", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", who is Petruchio's manservant?", "answer": "Grumio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c5", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian province of Manitoba?", "answer": "Winnipeg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b490049076251badbeaaa", "question": "The Treaty of Ghent was the peace treaty that ended which war?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049f03cf93664eb10486b7", "question": "What US state is home to the \"One Shell Square\" skyscraper?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb84", "question": "How long, in feet, is the Brooklyn Bridge?", "answer": "5,989 ft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c4", "question": "Who wielded a sword named Excalibur?", "answer": "King Arthur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0d", "question": "What year was comedian Jon Stewart born?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd2", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Hippomenes defeat in a footrace?", "answer": "Atalanta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a716", "question": "Lake of the Ozarks is located in which US state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a1", "question": "How many US states border West Virginia?", "answer": "5", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a666", "question": "What US city is home to the International UFO Museum and Research Center?", "answer": "Roswell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc1d7ec223966ae8f886e", "question": "The \"Tina\" in Tina Fey is short for what name?", "answer": "Stamatina", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7e09ff048f679a45ac06", "question": "Ataxophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Disorder or untidiness", "category": "science"}]